Mikalai Parafeniuk. Android developer.

July 18, 2014

Contact Information

- Email physmatman@gmail.com
- Skype parmikola
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=177491081
- GitHub https://github.com/ParafeniukMikalaj
- **Phone** +375 25 754 6119

Abstract

I have 2 year experience of Android development and 1.5 year of web development. Currently I work at Yandex. In 2014 I received CS bachelors degree from Faculty of Computer Network and Systems of BSUIR and CS degree from Yandex school of data analysis.

Work experience

• Yandex (since June 2013)

Currently I work at Yandex as android developer. I am developing and supporting authorization module, which is used in most of mobile applications of Yandex like browser, disk, maps, store and others. Also I participated in development of Yandex. Store and One Platform Foundation.

• Omegasoftware (January 2012 – June 2013)

At Omegasoftware I worked as web developer. I have participated in development of http://nostroy.ru/ where I used such technologies as Java, Spring Framework, Javascript, jQuery, ExtJs, MySql. I developed http://www.channelplace.net with usage of ASP.NET, MS SQL, Javascript, DevExpress. Also I developed proprietary software for advertisment and market analysis with usage of AST.NET, MS SQL, Javascript.

• AndersenSoft (July 2011 – December 2011)

AndersenSoft was my first place to work as programmer. There I participated in development of an android application for downloading and listening of audiobooks https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ru.librofon. At this company I acquired basic skills of Android development.

Education

I received my bachelors degree in Computer Science from Belarussian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics. I studied there from 2009 to 2014 at Faculty of Computer Networks and Systems on Informatics Department. University gave me strong math and programming background. At university I developed several interesting projects like cross-platform guitar tuner, rsa encryption utility, 1000 card game for Android, several sites, and lots of labs.

I have also studied in Yandex school of data analysis from 2012 to 2014 (http://shad.yandex.ru/). shad improved my math and algorithms background and gave knowledge in such fields like machine learning, natural language processing, parallel programming. In shad I completed a lot of interesting homeworks: statistical translation utility, interesting machine learning competitions at http://kaggle.com, implementation of lamdas on C++03, named entity recognition, OpenMP, MPI, Wikipedia Page Rank on MapReduce and a lot of others.

Technical skills

- Professional interests. Mobile, Web, machine learning, natural language processing, big data.
- **Programming languages**. Primary languages: Java, C#, Python. Also I use actively C++, C, Javascript and used Delphi, Groove, Scala and others some times.
- Frameworks and libraries. In Android I use all possibilities of SDK, but have no experience in NDK yet. Also I use support library, ActionBar Sherlock, Volley and others. I used the following Java frameworks: Spring, Play, Hibernate. Among .NET libraries I can enumerate ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, DevExpress.
- VCS. Today I use Git actively also I had a lot of experience with SVN and I used Mercurial some times.
- IDE. Android Studio, IntelliJ Idea, Eclipse, VisualStudio, Emacs, Vim.
- OS. In different periods of my life I used most popular operating systems: MacOS, Linux, Windows.

Open source development

After the completion of university and shad I am planning to contribute to open source development. As for now I have successfully participated in Google Summer Of Code students program in Apache organization in 2012.